live.
>> Like I say, welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and
answer. We open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain, for
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Sixth
day shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and restth the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor as
man's servant, nor as maid servant, nor
as ox, nor as ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. I read Exodus 20:es 1-1
17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen. So here on question and answer,
you can ask us a question and we'll
answer it according to the King James
Bible. And if we cannot find the answer,
we will seek further counsel to bring
you an answer at a later time. The
questions we will not answer are the
vague as well as the long scripture
questions and questions of debate. We're
not here to debate. We're here to spread
the true gospel of Jesus. So, please be
as direct as possible with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also keep in mind this is a
live stream. So feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking that
you please keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce you the
families that's on the panel this
evening. We got brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome, rest in peace.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone. Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> And we have brother Sean
or we have sister Casey with us. And we
have the guest caller. And I'm brother
Cornell. What is our first question of
the evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Um D.
Johnson asked for you to explain
Second Kings 17 verse 38.
And the covenant that I have made with
you, ye shall not forget, neither shall
ye fear other gods. So D. Johnson uh
warns to know how can we fear other
gods? If possible, please provide some
modern examples.
>> All right, so brother James, let's go to
that. Second Kings 17
and they're asking about the covenant
that was made here
as well as a God. So if you can pick it
up, brother, and the guest caller, take
it from there. Uh, is I believe Miss
Julia is for that one there.
>> Uh, mine.
>> No, it's the guest calls.
>> Not mine.
>> It's not the guest call. Is that you,
Brother Julius?
>> Okay, Brother Julius, it's not yours
either, right?
>> No, sir.
>> All right, then. Let's panel it.
Let's panel that uh 2 Kings 17 and 38
talking about the covenant there. But
pick it up at 37 James and let's read
down to it and let's open it up to the
panel.
>> Okay. 2 Kings 17
37 and 38 say, "And the statutes and the
ordinances and the law and the
commandment which he wrote for you, ye
shall observe to do forever more, and ye
shall not fear other gods."
>> Mhm.
>> And the covenant that I have made with
you, ye shall not forget, neither shall
ye fear other gods.
>> All right. So Lord is just telling you
don't don't fear those other gods. He's
the only one that we should be fearing
but not those other gods.
>> Yeah. You know cuz they had god you know
like Baal.
>> Yeah.
>> You know they
uh
they uh Israel burnt their children. I
think it was to Ba.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Then they had then they had another uh
uh they had
rim frame
>> rim.
>> They had
>> was a whole you can go in there and read
a whole lot of gods that they was made
that they made up.
>> Even uh we use go do one thing. When
Moses was in the mountain getting the
commandments
and uh uh
Israel asked that the uh the people
asked uh uh uh
Aaron to make them another god to bring
them back to Egypt. Let's give an
example what that mean. Somebody write
that down quick.
>> Exodus 32.
>> Okay. and start.
>> Start in which verse?
>> Exodus.
>> Should we start at one?
>> Let me see. We still still getting
there, brother. Exodus 32. And yeah,
that that's a good place to start,
brother James. Go right ahead.
>> Okay. Exodus 32:1 says, "And when the
people saw that Moses delayed to come
down out of the mount, the people
gathered themselves together unto Aaron,
and said unto him, Up, make us gods,
which shall go before us. For as for
this Moses, the man that brought us up
out of the land of Egypt, he what not
what is become of him." Mhm.
>> And Aaron said unto them, "Break off the
golden earrings, which are in the ears
of your wives, of your sons, and of your
daughters, and bring them unto me."
And all the people break off the golden
earrings which were in their ears, and
brought them unto Aaron. And he received
them at their hand, and fashioned it
with a graving tool, after he had made
it a molten calf. And they said, "These
be thy gods, O Israel, which brought
thee up out of the land of Egypt."
>> So now that so that's an example of the
so-called other god. There was not no
other gods.
It was all uh uh man-made.
>> Yep. He made all kind like the Egyptians
uh uh they had burials and cobras and uh
they just made statues of animals and
they uh uh uh and they fell out on their
knees and uh uh and they worshiping.
It's just like uh uh that maybe somebody
can bring up where they say that the
poor, you know, uh raised up a tree and
they made a god out of it and they and
they burnt. For first they had burnt
wood, made burnt it and kept warm by it.
Then
>> sound like Jeremiah.
>> Okay. And said then they fell on their
knees and worship the stock of a tree.
>> God out of it.
>> Jeremiah.
>> Okay. Let's search mode for that right
now. Okay.
>> Julius, you said Jeremiah 10.
>> Isaiah 44.
>> Okay. Isaiah 44.
Okay. And which let me see here.
>> Let's see. Isaiah 44.
>> Yeah. Pick it up at verse uh 15.
>> Okay.
Isaiah 44 and 15 says,
>> sorry 14. I'm sorry.
>> 14.
>> Okay. Isaiah 44:14 says, "He heth him
down cedars, and taketh the cyprress,
and the oak, which he strengthenth for
himself among the trees of the forest.
He planted an ash, and the rain doeth
nourish it. Then shall it be for a man
to burn, for he will take thereof, and
warm himself. Yay, he kindleth it, and
baketh bread. Yay, he maketh a god, and
worshiped it. He maketh it a graven
image, and fallth down there too.
>> He He burnt He burneth part of it in in
the fire, with part thereof he eateth
flesh. He roasteth roast, and is
satisfied. Yay, he warmeth himself, and
saith, Aha, I am warm. I have seen the
fire.
and the residue thereof he maketh a god,
even his grave in image. He fallth down
unto it, and worship it, and prayth unto
it, and saith, Deliver me, for thou art
my God.
>> They have not known nor understood, for
he has shut their eyes that they cannot
see, and their hearts that they cannot
understand.
and none considerth in his heart.
[clears throat] Neither is there
knowledge nor understanding to say, I
have burned part of it in the fire. Yay.
Also, I have baked bread upon the coals
thereof. I have roasted flesh and eaten
it. And shall I make the residue thereof
an abomination? Shall I fall down to the
stock of a tree?
>> So, let you know they make gods out of
all kind of things. Some of them out of
gold like the gold that came out the
earring of the Philipph people of Israel
when they come out of Egypt. This guy
made gods out of out of wood. Some of
them make gods out of stone. They are
not gods. They're handmade
objects that they called God and they
prayed to him.
So now
and the Lord said I should have no other
god before me. He's telling them, "You
should not have any of them handmade
gods that you make before me." Okay.
>> Yep.
Every nation we came across had their
own god.
>> Yep.
>> That's it.
>> All right.
>> We worship all.
>> Yep. Sure do.
All right. Well, we hope that that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question.
>> Our next one. Can you explain Revelation
16 13 and 14?
>> Brother Jerome, can you explain that
Revelation 16 13 and 14?
>> Let's go read it.
>> When you get it, go ahead.
>> Okay. Revelation 16 13 and 14 say, "And
I saw three unclean spirits like frogs
come out of the mouth of the dragon, and
out of the mouth of the beast, and out
of the mouth of the false prophet. For
they are the spirits of devils, working
miracles which go forth unto the kings
of the earth and of the whole world to
gather them to the battle of that great
day of God Almighty.
Yeah. Verse 14 kind of let you know what
it is. It said, "For they are the
spirits of devils." So these unclean
spirits are words that come out of the
mouth of the devil. And those words
uh are going to be in the mouths of the
you know the false prophet is is going
to be in the mouth of the military
leader of the uh European common market
and they going they going to be used
those words going to be used to
influence the world the kings of this
world that gather to battle the battle
of Armageddon you know and So now these
are the words of the devil right and an
example
that you know that's how the Satan
operate um Judas's scariot he used
Judas's scariot that way he influenced
Judas's scariot with words you know uh
to go against Jesus to betray him you
know so let's let's go look at uh John
13 verse 2 and then we going to tie with
Luke 22.
>> Okay. John 13
verse 2
says, "And supper being ended, the devil
having now put into the heart of Judas's
Scariot, Simon's son, to betray him."
>> Yeah. Put into this minds the heart he
talking about. Right. Now, let's tie
that with Luke
22 and read verse 2-5.
>> Okay. Luke 22:es
2-5
says, "And the chief priests and scribes
sought how they might kill him, for they
feared the people."
>> Talking about how they were going to
kill Jesus. Go ahead.
>> Then entered Satan into Judas's surname
as Scariot, being of the number of the
12.
>> Influencing his mind with words, you
know, but go ahead. Go ahead. And he
went his way and communed with the chief
priests and captains how he might betray
him unto them.
>> And they were glad and covenanted to and
and con combinated to give him money.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's all I got. You know,
that's all I got.
>> Yeah. You know, also in in the book of
James, it's talking about the the tongue
is an unruly evil
>> and it's set in in motion the forces of
nature.
>> Yeah.
>> Somebody grab that right quick.
>> James 3
>> and verse eight.
>> Um I think pick it up at verse five.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. James 3 and verse 5 says, "Even
so, the tongue is a little member and
boasteth great things. Behold, how great
a matter a little fire kindleth,
and the tongue is a fire, a world of
iniquity, so is the tongue among our
members, that it defileth the whole
body, and setth on fire the course of
nature, and it is set on fire of hell.
And so and so and so when it set on
anduh on fire the forces of nation you
know the uh uh uh you know with your
mouth you start finish that.
>> For every kind of beast and of birds and
of serpents and of things in the sea is
tamed and have been tamed of mankind.
But the tongue can no man tame. It is an
unruly evil full of deadly poison.
>> You see, [clears throat] that's why it
said of three unclean spirits come out
of the mouth of the beast, the false
prophet, and the dragon. Those are words
just like the brother said.
>> That's that tongue. Walls are started
with tongue. Fights are started with
tongue. You know, I'm going to do
something to you. Come on, let's do it.
You know what I mean?
>> Yeah. the rest the evil. Those are
unclean spirits like frogs.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Uh, next one. as a Catholic. I was
baptized as an infant, but now that I am
an adult, I've seen in other faiths
people being submerged in water, which
is correct.
>> All right, guess caller. So, they was
baptized as a baby and then they see
adults submerged in water. Which one is
the proper way to baptize?
>> I think that's Michael. Uh, no it is the
guest caller.
>> Yeah, guest caller. Go right ahead.
>> What the whole thing is the whole uh uh
uh uh motion that the Catholic Church do
do is wrong.
Not only do they sprinkle you, then they
quote, "I baptize you in the name of the
father and the name of the son and in
the name of the holy ghost." So and you
so for two things you baptized wrong
without because you should be totally
submerged.
>> And the other thing is if you was a baby
you was baptized too young.
You shouldn't nobody should so you
should get totally submerged. But again
too the uh uh age uh nobody should be
baptized
under 20. And I'm going to show you why
is because because the Lord hold you
responsible when you're 20 years old or
older. He showed that when he brought
Israel out of Egypt. Let's go into
Numbers the 14th chapter
and we're going to read verse 22
24.
Then we're going to skip down to verse
29.
Okay. Numbers 14 22- 24.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. Numbers 14. Numbers 14 22- 24 say
because all those men which have seen my
glory and my miracles which I did in
Egypt and in the wilderness and have
tempted me now these 10 times and have
not hearkened to my voice.
Surely they shall not see the land which
I swear unto their fathers, neither
shall any of them that provoke me see
it. But my servant Caleb, because he had
another spirit with him, and hath
followed me fully. Him will I bring into
the land wherein to he went, and his
seed shall possess it.
Verse 29 says, "Your carcasses shall
fall in this wilderness, and all that
were numbered of you according to the
whole number from 20 years old and
upward, which have murmured against me."
Now, I let you know, so you had some 18
and 19 year old murmuring, too.
But the Lord didn't hold him
responsible. They held you 20 because he
said now those from 20 years and older,
they ain't going to get in the land. So
only two people
when they was uh uh got in the land with
Joshua and Caleb
from 20 years and older.
So when when uh uh Joshua took Israel in
Egypt
except for Caleb, everybody else was 19
years old and under. Why? because that
let us know that God hold you
responsible for 20 and and and and
you're charged with your behavior. So
the first thing is to dump them in the
water totally submerged. But you don't
do that until they 20 years old and
older
is because they're doing two things. God
set the showed us when he uh when he
hold us responsible then again too
you're growing enough to know that you
are getting into a blood covenant.
>> Yep.
>> Now the third thing is is when you get
ready to bapt somebody baptize people
the Catholic church and most of the
people in the uh uh uh Roman
Christianity and they get ready to
baptize you. They said, "I baptize you
in the name of the Father, the name of
the Son, and the name of the Holy Ghost.
They put you in the water." Jesus told
you to baptize in the name of the
Father, Son, and the Holy Ghost. He
didn't say, "Quote me."
>> So, in order to let you know how what
how you what name you should be called
when you put them in the water, let's go
and look at it right quick. Let's go
into Acts the 7th chapter. Read verse
36-38.
>> Okay. Acts Acts 2:es 36-38
say, "Therefore, let all the house of
Israel know assuredly that God hath made
that same Jesus whom ye have crucified,
both Lord and Christ."
Now when they had heard this, they were
pricricked in their heart, and said unto
Peter and to the rest of the apostles,
men and brethren, what shall we do? Then
Peter said unto them, repent
[clears throat] and be baptized, every
one of you, in the name of Jesus Christ,
for the remissions of sins, and ye shall
receive the gift of the Holy Ghost.
So he didn't say he didn't quote what
Jesus said. He did what Jesus commanded.
>> He was baptized in a name.
>> So Jesus come in his father's name
>> and he said, "I'mma pray to the father
and he going to send you the holy ghost
in my name." The father's name was
Jesus. And so if Jesus come in his name,
then Jesus' name became Jesus. And if
you send the uh Holy Ghost in Jesus'
name, then he come. There was an angel
really. He came in the name of Jesus. So
now one other place, let's go into Acts
the 19th chapter and read verses 1
through 5 and let's see how Paul
baptized people.
>> Okay. Acts 19:1-5 says, "And it came to
pass that while Apollos was at Corinth,
Paul having passed through the upper
coast, came to Ephesus, and finding
certain disciples, he said unto them,
Have ye received the Holy Ghost since ye
believed?" And they said unto him, We
have not so much as heard, whether there
be any Holy Ghost. And he said unto
them, "Unto what then were ye baptized?"
And they said, "Unto John's baptism?"
>> Then said Paul, John verily baptized
with the baptism of repentance, saying
unto the people that they should believe
on him which should come after him, that
is on Christ Jesus. When they heard
this, they were baptized in the name of
the Lord Jesus.
Yep.
>> So now these are two major the two major
apostles.
They put you in the water. He said, "I
baptize you in the name of Jesus." Then
they put you in the water. So now but
but before that happened, I mean totally
submerge you in the water. But they
shouldn't do it before you 20 years old.
Then again too,
if you are a male, you should be
circumcised before you get baptized
>> because you are not under the covenant
that God made with Abraham. So how is it
that you going to become under a
covenant that came out of the covenant
that God made with Abraham?
>> So you should be circumcised.
>> Sure. Because uh you know I'm a
Christian. You know what? Well, then
they tell you that no uncircumcised
people, no uncircumcised person should
uh uh uh uh
take part in the Passover.
>> I want to show you is I think that was
it. I think it's 1 Corinthian
7 and five and seven or seven and five.
Let me tell you who the pastor within.
>> Yeah. Uh 1 Corinthians 5 and 7. Sir,
>> read it.
>> It says, "Purge out therefore the old
leaven, that ye may be a new lump, as ye
are unleavened, for even Christ our
Passover is sacrificed for us."
So if you going to be baptized in a new
covenant, you have to be baptized in
Jesus in Jesus' name.
And if you going to be baptized in him,
then you are baptized in our Passover
because it is his blood that caused the
Lord to pass over our sins.
>> Amen. And he said, Exodus the 12th
chapter, there shall no uncircumcised
male take part of the Passover. That's
all I have to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. We hope
that answered their question as we
continue to move on to our next
question.
>> Yes. Next one. Most churches teach the
trinity trinity doctrine, but IoG
teaches only two in the godhead. Why?
>> Oh, Julia, shed that light, brother.
>> That is because the Bible teaches that
there's only two in the godhead.
Let's let's give you an example. Let's
go uh to second John uh 2 John the 2
chapter.
Brother James
>> second John
>> this
>> let's see here
2 John 2 and what do verse 9 say brother
>> it says whosoever transgresseth and
abideth not in the doctrine of Christ
hath not God. He that abideth in the
doctrine of Christ, he hath both the
father and the son. Notice that key word
there, both. It didn't say there are
three. It said both the father and the
son. Let's go to um so much of this
Psalm 110. Psalm 110 and we're going to
read just verse one. Psalm 110 and verse
one.
because we getting it out of the mouth
of more uh uh not just two but we going
to get it out of the mouth of three
witnesses
when you get it. Psalm 110 and verse
one. Go ahead.
>> The Lord said unto my Lord, sit thou at
my right hand until I make thine enemies
thy foottool.
>> Sit thou at my right hand till I make
thine enemies thy foottool. The father
said unto the son, that's two, only two
in the godhead. Hebrews 1.
And I got one place after this. Hebrews
1. And we're going to read verse 8.
Hebrews 1 and verse 8.
Look what the father said to the son. Go
ahead.
But unto the Son he saith, "Thy throne,
oh God, is forever and ever. A scepter
of righteousness is the scepter of thy
kingdom."
>> So the father called the son God
because there's only two in the Godhead.
No such thing as God the Father, God the
Son, and God the Holy Ghost. My last
place, let's go to First Corinthians the
first chapter. Why don't you read why
don't you read a little more of that
where it say
God thy God?
>> Yep. We we read that verse eight. Yeah.
We going to read verse N.
>> Thou has loved righteousness and hated
iniquity. Therefore, God, even thy God,
hath anointed me with the oil of
gladness above thy fellows,
>> Father and the Son, the Godhead.
Now, we go to Thank you, guest caller.
First Corinthians,
the first chapter. And as a note, you
can read all of Paul's opening and all
of his writings. He going to say the
same thing even in the book of Romans.
But I'm on 1 Corinthians the first
chapter.
And look at this greeting that Paul
says. 1 Corinthians 1 and verse three.
>> Grace be unto you and peace from God our
father and from the Lord Jesus Christ.
>> Only two in the Godhead, sisters and
brothers. And you can read that in
Colossians 1, Philippians 1, Galatians
1. uh 1 Thessalonians 1 and Timothy 1,
the same exact greeting. Now Paul the
apostle to the Gentiles kept it at two.
Where did we get three from?
That trinity teaching came from the
council of Na in 321 32 uh5 AD and in
381 AD they made the Holy Ghost equal to
the Godhead and the Holy Ghost is none
other than the angel that stands in the
presence of God. He's an angel and not
God. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question as we move on to
our next question. Uh, next one. I have
heard the Lord hates six things. Do you
know what they are?
>> Guess caller, please weigh in.
>> Go to Proverbs the 6th chapter, read
verses 16 and 17. 16 through 19.
>> Okay. It says,
>> "These six things doeth the Lord hate.
Yay, seven are an abomination unto him.
A proud look, a lying tongue, and hands
that shed innocent blood, and heart that
devisth wicked imaginations, feet that
be swift in running to mischief, a false
witness that speaketh lies, and he that
sweth discord among brethren.
>> That's all of them right there. all six
of them.
That's in Proverbs 6 16-19.
Okay.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we continue to keep moving.
>> Yes. Uh what does Romans 5 verse 19
mean? For by one man's disobedience
many were made sinners.
>> Right. Let's go to that Romans.
Let's go to that Romans five.
And when we get to that Romans five,
let's pick it up at that verse 19
because that's the one in question and
then we'll uh skip up a little bit. So,
Romans 5 and 19.
>> Go ahead, brother.
For as by one man's disobedience, many
were made sinners, so by the obedience
of one shall many be made righteous.
>> Okay? So by one man's disobedient, that
happened to be Adam, our forefather, our
father, way in the back to Genesis,
brother. Let's go there and let's see
what happened. For as by one man's
disobedience, many were made sinners,
because all have sinned and come short
of the glory of God because of that
mishap in Genesis.
So by the obedience of one shall many be
made righteous as one that came to die
for the sins of the whole world to help
us out. Let's go to Genesis 3, brother.
When you get there, let's pick it up at
that verse. Uh let's see where the fall
began to take place. Pick it up at that
verse six. Go ahead.
>> And when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food, and that it was pleasant
to the eyes, and a tree to be desired to
make one wise, she took of the fruit
thereof, and did eat, and gave it also
unto her husband with her, and he did
eat.
>> Read seven. And the eyes of them both
were open, and they knew that they were
naked, and they sewed fig leaves
together, and made themselves aprons.
>> So that began the beginning of the fall
right there. When the woman listened to
what Satan said, took it to her husband,
and he went along with it, that began
the fall. And then they were naked, and
the Lord knew that. And the Lord said in
that verse 11, read that, and then we
going to skip to 17. Go ahead.
>> And he said, "Who told thee that thou
was naked? Hast thou eaten of the tree
whereof I commanded thee that thou
shouldest not eat?"
>> And who'd he blame it on? 12.
>> And the man said, "The woman thou gavest
to be with me. She gave me of the tree,
and I did eat."
>> Yes, but hey, he didn't have to eat of
it. She didn't have no gun on him. Skip
down to verse 17. Go ahead.
>> And unto Adam he said, Because thou has
hearkened unto the voice of thy wife,
and hast eaten of the tree of which I
commanded thee, saying, thou shalt not
eat of it, cursed is the ground for thy
sake, and sorrow shalt thou eat of it
all the days of thy life.
>> Yep. So that is what brought the
disobedience on the table that fall
there. Then it brought death in. So that
created a problem. But let's go to 1
Corinthians 15. 1 Corinthians 15
and let's pick it up brother at that
verse uh 40 I think 45. 1 Corinthian 15
and verse 45.
Go ahead.
And so it is written, the first man,
Adam, was made a living soul. The last
Adam was made a quickening spirit.
>> Yes. And that's that's Jesus. We talking
about that second one. Go ahead.
>> How be it, that was not first which is
spiritual, but that which is natural,
and afterward that which is spiritual.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The first man is of the earth, earthy.
The second man is the Lord from heaven.
>> Yes. So that started to fall there. But
we needed the Lord to come and die for
our sins to help us because we were all
on our way to destruction without his
blood, his death, and his resurrection.
But in that Romans 5 is what they had in
question too, right? Romans 5.
>> Romans 5 verse 19.
All right. And let's pick it up um at
that verse uh read that verse six for me
there. Romans 5
and verse six. Go ahead, brother.
>> For when we were yet without strength,
in due time Christ died for the ungodly.
>> Yes, that was to help out that
disobedience. Uh go ahead. Verse eight.
But God commandeth his love towards us,
and that while we were yet sinners,
Christ died for us.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Much more then, being now justified by
his blood, we shall be saved from wrath
through him.
>> Yes. Thank God. Go ahead.
For if when we were enemies, we were
reconciled to God by death, by the death
of his son, much more being reconciled,
we should be saved by his life.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And not only so, but we also joy in God
through our Lord Jesus Christ, by whom
we have now received the atonement.
>> Yes, the supreme recovery. And read that
verse well for me.
Wherefore, as by one man sin entered
into the world, and death by sin, and so
death passed upon all men, for that all
have sinned.
>> Yep. So, by Adam's sin, that one man's
disobedience brought it all on us, and
therefore all have sinned.
And that's all I got. Anybody else?
All right, we're gonna leave it right
there, Sister Deborah, with a time check
to our next question.
>> Yes, the time is 811. The next question.
How do you keep the faith when diagnosed
with an incurable fatal disease?
>> That's a good qu question, brother Dre,
because we have a lot of sickness
amongst us. And so, how do you keep your
faith, brother?
diagnosed with a incurable fatal
disease,
you got to believe the word of God. You
got to read the word and believe it. You
got to believe this word because this
word
>> will tell you what you need to trust in
and that is God. So, let's go over to uh
Job 19. Job suffered a lot of things. I
want you to see what Job said while he
was suffering, though.
Job 19 and pick it up at verse 25. Read
25 to 27. Go ahead, brother.
>> For I know that my redeemer liveth and
that he shall stand at the latter day
upon the earth.
>> And though after my skin worms destroy
this body, yet in my flesh shall I see
God. Mhm.
>> Whom I shall see for myself and mine
eyes shall behold and not another.
Though my reigns be consumed within me.
So whatever Job was suffering, he said
he knows, he don't believe, he knows his
redeemer liveth and that he shall stand
upon the earth at the latter day.
>> Yes. Will raise us up. And this is what
we got to understand. No ma because it's
appointed for once for all men to die.
That's what it says in first Corinthians
15. Let's just go read that. 1
Corinthians 15 and pick it up at verse
21.
Go ahead.
>> Okay. It says, "For since by man came
death, by man came also the resurrection
of the dead. Mhm.
>> For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
>> Mhm.
>> But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits. Afterward, they that
are Christ at his coming.
>> At his coming. So no matter what, it's
appointed onto all of us to die. And
then there's the judgment. Unless you
hear at the coming of the Lord, then you
will be changed. But nonetheless, while
we in this flesh, we are walking in this
faith and to the end. The book says in
Matthew 24, "He that endures to the end,
the same shall be saved." Let's go to
Isaiah 25.
I want to read verse read verse 8 and
nine, brother. When you get it, go
ahead.
Isaiah 25:8 and9.
>> He will swallow up death in victory.
>> And the Lord God will wipe away tears
off all faces,
>> and the rebuke of his people shall he
take away from off the earth. For the
Lord has spoken it. So the Lord spoke
this and we got to believe that he is
going to swallow up this in victory and
he's going to raise the dead and change
the living and those that are faithful
he will raise up to be in the kingdom
with him. This is what this walk is all
about all the way to the end. Let's go
one last place. Let's go to Revelation
21 and we going to read verses 3 to
five.
When you get there, go ahead, brother.
>> And I heard a great voice out of heaven,
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them, and be
their God."
>> Go ahead.
And God shall wipe away all tears from
their eyes. And there shall be no more
death, neither sorrow, nor crying,
neither shall there be any more pain,
for the former things are passed away.
And he said, and he that sat upon the
throne said, Behold, I make all things
new. And he said unto me, "Write, for
these words are true and faithful,
>> and these words are written for us and
know they are true. And if we got faith
in them, we going to walk in them and
and hope in them." And uh also the Lord
can heal, but if he don't heal,
nonetheless, keep your faith and endure
until the end. That's all I got.
>> Yes, sir. Eat that face. Hold on.
>> I'd like to make a statement.
>> Yes, sir.
>> There's one thing. You know, whether you
uh uh uh die early or late, you're
supposed to prepare for
the resurrection
because everybody here is temporary.
Everything around us is temporary.
So if you feel that you're not going to
live much longer, then prepare for the
eternal life because you will live
forever. Don't lose the faith and you
will live forever as God. But if you
lose your faith, you going to still be
raised and live forever, but you going
to be living in the lake of fire.
So think about that.
Keep the faith. B for eternity.
>> Yeah.
>> On the good side of the kingdom as God.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Yes.
Okay. We hope that that answer your
question as we continue to move on.
>> Moving on. When God the Father comes
down to earth with all the holy angels
in Revelations 21
1-3
with all the holy angels, will all the
holy angels come with him or will some
of them remain in heaven?
>> All right. And God the Father comes down
to earth. Will all the holy angels come
or will some lay back? Brother Jerome,
>> I think you kind of got it um a little
mixed up. It's It's not the father
that's gonna come with all the holy
angels. It's actually going to be the
son, Jesus Christ. But let's go read uh
the verse that you gave and then I'll
show you the verse where it's the son
that's coming with all the holy angels,
not the father. Okay? So go to uh
Revelations 21. Read that verse 1 and
three.
It says, "And I saw a new heaven and a
new earth, for the first heaven and the
first earth were passed away, and there
was no more sea.
And I saw John, and I, John, saw the
holy city, New Jerusalem, coming down
from God out of heaven, prepared as a
bride adorned for her husband.
And I heard a great voice out of heaven,
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
with is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them and be
their God."
Now, these verses here, that is talking
about the father, but this not going to
take place until a thousand years after
the Lord come. Okay. So now let's go
read the verses where it's the son
that's coming with all the angels. Let's
go to Matthews
and we're going to read verse 31.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
Matthew 25 and31 says, "When the Son of
Man shall come in his glory and all the
holy angels with him, then shall he sit
upon the throne of his glory."
Yeah. So that's that's Jesus Christ, the
son that's coming with all the holy
angels. So by the time the father get
here, you know, the Lord going to get
the kingdom together and then within a
thousand years, he going to get that
kingdom together and then he going to
present it to the father after after
judgment day after he put death and hell
in the fire. All of that then he going
to present it to the father and that's
when the father going to come them
verses that you was mentioning in that
revelations 21. He going to come with
the holy city, New Jerusalem, with the
uh streets of gold and the many
mansions. Yeah.
>> Well, but that's all I got.
>> Well, indeed.
>> All the other parts he asking, will any
be left?
>> No. All the all is an absolute.
>> There won't be no angel left. In fact,
when Jesus come and all the holy angels,
the father is going to be up there by
himself.
>> Yeah.
>> For a thousand [clears throat] years
before he come cuz all of the holy
angels will be here on earth.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
Man, wisdom is a beautiful thing to
have. Okay, let's move on to our next
question.
>> Uh, next one. Did Jesus go to hell
between his death and resurrection?
>> So when Jesus died and the time he came
out the grave, did he go to hell,
brother Julius?
>> Contrary to uh popular teaching, no, he
went to the grave.
Let's show you. Let's go. Let's look at
what the book say with and then we going
to date it. Matthew the 27th chapter.
Matthew chapter 27, James. And we're
gonna get right to the point. After they
had crucified him, Matthew 27 and pick
this up at verse 50.
>> Verse 50.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. Jesus, when he had cried again
with a loud voice, yielded up the ghost.
>> So he died. Skip down to 57 and go all
the way to 60. Go ahead.
When the evening was come, there came a
rich man of Arya named Joseph, who also
himself was Jesus's disciple.
>> Uh-huh.
>> He went to Pilate and begged the body of
Jesus. Then Pilate commanded the body to
be delivered.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And when Joseph had taken the body, he
wrapped it in a clean linen cloth and
laid it in his own new tomb, which he
had hewned out in the rock. and he
rolled a great stone to the door of the
suppl and departed.
>> So Jesus went to the grave. He went to
the tomb. Joseph knew tomb. How long was
he there? Brother James, let's go to
Matthew the 12th chapter and look at
what it was prophesied he would be.
We're going to read verses 38-4.
Because people keep saying he went to
hell. Hell is a state of condition.
Matthew 12 38-40. When you get it, go
ahead.
Then certain of the scribes and of the
Pharisees answered, saying, "Master, we
would see a sign from thee." But he
answered and said unto them, "An evil
and adulterous generation seeketh after
a sign, and there shall no sign be given
to it, but the sign of the prophet
Jonas." Go ahead. For as Jonas was three
days and three nights in the whale's
belly, so shall the Son of Man be three
days and three nights in the heart of
the earth.
>> Not down up in hell. He went to the
grave. Sisters and brothers, they're in
Jerusalem.
It was prophesied. Two more places
quickly. Isaiah 53, bro.
Jesus was was crucified and the two
thieves was crucified with him. Isaiah
53 and verse 9. That's all we got. Verse
9.
And he made his grave with the wicked
and with the rich in his death because
he had done no violence. Neither was any
deceit in his mouth.
>> So he was crucified and Joseph took the
body and put it in their own new tomb.
My last place. First Peter, first Peter
chapter 3 and let's look at when Jesus
went so people say to hell.
First Peter, when you get it, my
brother, first Peter 3 and pick it up at
verse 18 to 20. When you get it, go
ahead.
For Christ also hath once suffered for
sins, the just for the unjust, that he
might bring us to God, being put to
death in the flesh, but quickened by the
spirit.
>> Uh-huh.
>> By which also he went and preached unto
the spirits in prison.
>> Uh-huh. would sometime were disobedient
when other when once the longsuffering
of God waited in the days of Noah while
the ark
>> when waited in the days of Noah while
the ark was a preparing wherein few that
is eight souls were saved by water
>> that was Jesus back there preaching to
them evil angels in those days in the
days of Noah
not after his death sisters and brothers
that came so much longer afterwards,
sisters and brothers. So no, he went to
the grave and he was there for three
days and three nights and he resurrected
on the third day just like the prophets
wrote about it. That's all I got.
Anybody else?
>> I just I want to show you the error. He
said he speak to the prison the the
spirits in prison.
>> Yeah. God say he angel spirits
but man is a living soul.
So the spirit that was in prison like
Julius said those was the angels during
the time and like the book said angels
during the time when Noah then was
building the ark he got unruly
>> Jesus had to go deal with them in Noah's
day they are spirit man is not a spirit
man is a soul. Yes, sir. Only got
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. So, we hope that answered
your question and we're gonna move on to
our next one with a time check.
>> Yes. The time is 8:26.
In the Old Testament, when making a
sacrifice from a cow, goat, sheep, or
ram. It was said the Lord wanted the fat
to be burned separately.
Is this true? And why?
All right. So in the Old Testament when
making the sacrifices
said that God wanted the fat to be
burned separately. Guess call them.
>> Well, we're going to look at what what
the book say. Let's go to Leviticus
3 chapter.
We're going to read verses 9 through 11
and then we're going to skip down and
read 16.
>> Okay. Was that Leviticus 3?
Yeah. Mhm.
>> Okay. Leviticus 3:es 9-11 say, "And he
shall offer of the sacrifice of the
peace offering, an offering made by fire
unto the Lord, the fat thereof, and the
whole rump. It shall be taken off hard
by the backbone, and the fat that
coverth the inwards, and all the fat
that is upon the inwards,
and the two kidneys, and fat that is
upon them, which is by the flanks, and
the call above the liver with the
kidneys, it shall be taken away.
And the priest shall burn it up upon the
altar. It is the food of the offering
made by fire unto the Lord.
>> Verse 16.
>> And the priest shall burn them upon the
altar. It is the food of the offering
made by fire for a sweet savor. All the
fat is the Lord's.
>> Okay. Well, that's what it said. You and
the thing is you asked the question why.
Why don't you make a note of that? And
so when you see the Lord, ask him.
>> That's all I got to say.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we keep on moving right along.
>> Moving on. Luke 3 verse 13. What is
exact no more mean?
>> Exacts
be doing what is expected of you or what
is required. But let's go into because I
believe that's in Luke 3.
Luke 3
and let's read that verse 13 and then
we're going to
skip up. Read pick it up verse 9,
brother. Let's read down into that 13
because this right here is a statement
that should scare the people. Go ahead.
That's Luke 3:9.
And now also the axe is laid unto the
root of the trees. Every tree therefore
which bringeth not forth good fruit is
he down and cast into the fire.
>> All right. So these trees, we talking
about some people here. Look at verse
10. Go ahead.
>> And the people also asked him, saying,
"What shall we do then?"
>> Uh-huh. He answered and saith unto them,
he that hath two coats, let him impart
to him that hath none. And he that hath
meat, let him do likewise.
>> All right? So, this is just being time
and being considerate of others. If you
got two coats, hey, you see your brother
ain't got none, give him one. And if you
got something to eat, meat, and you see
your brother don't have nothing, give
him a little something, too. Verse 12.
Then came also publicans to be baptized
and said unto him, "Master, what shall
we do?"
>> All right. These were some publicans too
can be tax collectors. So they wanted to
know too. They came to be baptized and
they said, "Hey, what should we do?" And
what was said in 13
>> and he said unto them, "Exact
which is appointed you."
>> All right. So exact no more. Hey, what
is required for you to collect, you just
collect that. You don't have to be
trying to go over collecting from the
people. Collect what is required of you.
Verse 14.
>> And the soldiers likewise demanded of
him, saying, "And what shall we do?" And
he said unto them, "Do violence to no
man, neither accuse any any falsely, and
be content with your wages."
So this is staying within the guidelines
of what it is you should do. The
soldiers, hey, don't do violence to no
man. Neither accuse any falsely. Don't
lie nobody. And be content with what it
is that you have. But I want to go into
that Micah 6 and read that seven and 8
just to see what is required of us.
Micah 6. We covered the publicans and
not the soldiers. And let's just give
Micah 6 and read that verse. Uh I'm
sorry. Micah 6 read 7 and 8. Brother, go
ahead. Will the Lord be pleased with
thousands of rams? Or with 10 thousands
of rivers of oil? Shall I give my
firstborn for my transgression, the
fruit of my body for the sin of my soul?
>> What do the Lord require?
He has showed thee, oh man, what is
good. And what do the Lord require of
thee? But to do justly, and to love
mercy, and to walk humbly with thy God.
>> And that's being obedient, and keeping
his laws, statutes, and commandments all
tied up in there. When you are walking
with God, you have to do what he say.
Uh, anybody else? That's all I got.
Okay, we're gonna leave it right there,
Sister Deborah, as we move on to our
next one.
>> Moving on. Jesus fulfilled the law, why
tell people they have to keep it?
>> That question is very popular, Brother
Dre. If Jesus fulfilled the law, then
how come people are telling other people
they have to keep the law?
>> Let's see what Jesus said. Let's go over
to uh a very popular verse they like to
read too. Let's go to Matthew the 5th
chapter.
>> Matthew 5
and
I want you to start at verse 17.
Go ahead, brother.
Think not that I am come to destroy the
law or the prophets. I'm not come to
destroy but to fulfill.
>> And this is where they stop at. So when
they read that and stop right there,
they don't know the rest of what Jesus
is saying. But we also going to look at
what he fulfilled. But continue to read,
brother. Verse 18.
For verily I say unto you, till heaven
and earth pass, one jot or one tit in no
wise pass from the law till all be
fulfilled. Go ahead. Whosoever therefore
shall break one of these least
commandments, and shall teach men so, he
shall be called the least in the kingdom
of heaven. But whosoever shall do and
teacheth them, the same shall be called
great in the kingdom of heaven.
>> Now, this don't sound like he threw
those commandments away. It sound like
he's telling you who's going to be great
in the kingdom of heaven and who's going
to be the least. And that least is in
the lake of fire. But let's look at
something else here. Let's look at what
he did fulfill. Let's go over to Luke
24.
Luke 24
and pick it up at verse 44. Luke 24 and
44.
Luke 24 and 44.
>> Go ahead and read it when you get there,
brother.
And he said unto them, "These are the
words which I spake unto you while I was
yet with you, that all things must be
fulfilled, which were written in the law
of Moses and in the prophets and in the
psalms concerning me."
>> This is what he fulfilled the things
that was written of him that he was to
do. and there's still more to fulfill,
but he fulfilled those things concerning
him. But he's going to give you detail.
Go ahead, brother.
>> Then open he their understanding that
they might understand the scriptures.
>> Mhm.
>> And said unto them, thus it is written
and thus it behold Christ to suffer and
to rise from the dead the third day.
>> This is what he fulfilled.
He fulfilled that he was going to suffer
and rise again the third day. Go ahead.
>> And the and that repentance and
remission of sins should be preached in
his name among all nations beginning at
Jerusalem.
>> And I've heard some people say that say
they believers in Christ say they don't
need to repent.
What? That's crazy. And so anybody
telling you that you don't have to keep
the commandments, they are trying to get
you cut off and put into the lake of
fire. That's all I got.
>> Yeah, that's right. And Dre, like we
know, Lord said he wrote the
commandments with his own finger.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So why would you then be able to throw
them away? Okay. Thank you for that,
brother. And sister Deborah, our next
question.
>> Yes. Uh moving on. More muddy waters
says, "There are many things that
classify one as an abomination.
Do you become one right away? Can you
still go to the kingdom of God?"
>> Right, Jerome? It's abomination. And do
you still have a shot at the kingdom of
God?
When you commit any kind of abomination
according to the word of God, then
you're making yourself abominable in the
eyes of the Lord. But the thing the the
most important thing you need to
understand is you can repent.
[clears throat]
You don't have to continue in that
abomination. You can repent. Okay? And
when you repent, the Lord will forgive
even the abominations that you have
committed. Okay? And there is one thing
the Lord say he ain't going to forgive
and that's sin against the Holy Ghost.
But you can repent. You can repent for
that too. The key is to repent. Stop.
Change, you know. Yeah. But let's read
one verse. Let's go to Ezekiel chapter
14. Read verse six.
Ezekiel chapter 14 verse 6 says,
"Therefore say unto the house of Israel,
thus sayeth the Lord God, repent and
turn yourselves from your idols, and
turn away your faces from all your
abominations."
>> And he will forgive if you do that.
That's all I got on.
All right, we gonna leave it right there
as we move on to our next question.
>> Yes. Uh, he also asks or she, "Is it
fine to work somewhere that sells
unclean food? There is not a lot of
options these days in food jobs.
>> All right. Is it fine to work somewhere
that sells unclean foods? There are not
a lot of options during these days.
Yeah, it's kind of tough out there
working. Well, we know you have to keep
the dietary law and don't eat any of
that unclean food and wear gloves when
possible. Anybody else?
>> Well, the whole thing is it ain't
nothing but a job.
>> It's a job.
>> And I tell you tell you jobs that people
have to do. Dead bodies are unclean.
>> Yeah. But when people die, somebody have
to bury you.
>> Yep. That's right.
>> Yeah. So
>> just like that. Same thing with the
food.
>> If you don't eat it, you're okay.
>> Yep.
All right. Hope that answered your
question there. Our next one.
>> Next one. J Master as asks, "Can you
please explain the talents in the
parable of talents?" And Matthew 25:15
and 16
and 24 and 25 are given.
>> All right. Matthew 25. Let's go there to
that Matthew 25, James. And they ask
about that 15- 16 and that 24-2.
Let's open it up to the panel. But let's
start at that verse 14 and read 14 and
16, brother.
>> Okay. It says, "For the kingdom of
heaven is as a man traveling into a far
country who called his own servants and
delivered unto him unto them his goods.
And unto one he gave five talents, to
another two, and to another one. to
every man according to his several
ability and straightway took his
journey. [clears throat] Then he that
had received the five talents went and
traded with the same and made them other
five talents.
>> All right. Uh skip down to 24. It's open
to the panel guest caller.
>> This is all this is talking about is
spiritual gifts. But you read the 24 and
25 first.
>> All right.
>> Then he which had received the one
talent came and said, Lord, I knew thee
that thou art an hard man, reaping where
thou hast not sown, and gathering where
thou hast not straw. And I was afraid,
and went and hid thy talent in the
earth. Lo, there thou has that is thine.
So now this don't have nothing to do
with money. It's spiritual gifts because
the Lord give people spiritual gifts,
something they can contribute to the
gospel and they don't do nothing with
it. But let me let's let's look at let's
look at a few of these gifts. Go to
first Corinthians the 12th chapter.
We're going to read verse one and we're
going to skip down to four.
And once you get through with that,
we'll skip some more.
>> Okay. 1 Corinthians 12:1 says, "Now
concerning spiritual gifts, brethren, I
would not have you ignorant."
Verse 4 says,
>> "Now there are diversities of gifts, but
the same spirit."
Now skip down to verse 8 from 8 to 11.
Verse 8 says, "For to one is given by
the Spirit, the word of wisdom, to
another the word of knowledge by the
same Spirit, to another faith by the
same Spirit, to another the gifts of
healing by the same Spirit. To another
the working of miracles, to another
prophecy, to another discerning of
spirits, to another diverse kinds of
tongues, to another the interpretation
of tongues.
But all these workketh that one, and the
self-same spirit, dividing to every man
se severely severally all as he will.
So for
>> what verse was that?
>> That was verse 11, sir.
>> Did you finish it?
>> I finished verse 11. Yes.
>> Yeah. Well, that's enough. What it
saying is God give you gifts, spiritual
gifts. And there are many other gifts
and you don't use them. You might be a
good musician, but you played all
secular music. You don't play no music
for the Lord.
might be a a a writer,
good writer, but you don't use that
talent to write spiritual uh information
that can edify people.
So now the ones that use it and God set
up his Jesus and his kingdom on this
earth, they going to give them h certain
rulerships over certain cities and and
they have certain jobs like the twel
apostles. They going to be uh judge of
the 12 tribes of Israel.
So that's all it is. Spiritual gifts.
God give you a gift, use it to enhance
his word, he will give you a job in his
kingdom. But if you decide, well, you
know, to nobody believe it anyway, so I
ain't going to even speak about this
word of God. Then once God come, you
might be in the first resurrection if
you don't break your law. But you ain't
got no job. That's all I have to say.
Yes. Is Ephesians the fourth chapter the
same thing? Ephesians the fourth chapter
when he when he descended and gave gifts
on men.
>> Yeah.
>> Ephesians 4 James and pick it up at
verse 8 and then
>> Okay. Ephesians 4:8 saith, wherefore he
saith, when he ascended up on high, he
led captivity captive, and gave gifts
unto men.
>> Verse 11.
>> And he gave some apostles, and some
prophets, and some evangelists, and some
pastors, and teachers.
>> Continue to 13. for the perfecting of
the saints, for the work of the
ministry, for the edifying of the body
of Christ,
till we all come in the unity of the
faith and of the knowledge of the son of
God, unto a perfect man, unto the
measure of the stature of the fullness
of Christ. Like guest caller said them
talents, you know, them talents which is
still gifts for the edification of the
body of Christ to be used
for the church, for the purpose of the
church, for the perfecting of the
saints.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> All right.
>> All right. So, we uh hope that answered
your question, Sister Deborah. New
territory.
>> New territory. We are now into tonight's
Q&A for Wednesday, June the 3, 2026.
Be alert as in Revelations 1 vers 15 and
16. Can you please explain what is meant
by Jesus' voice is like the sound of
many waters and the meaning of the seven
stars in Jesus' hand.
>> All right. Revelation 1
and verse 15 and 16. So they want two
answers there. What does verse 15 mean?
And what does verse 16 mean? So when you
get there, Brother James, go ahead.
Let's open it up to the panel.
>> Okay. And his feet like unto the fine
brass as if they were burned in a
furnace, and his voice as the sound of
many waters.
And he had in his right hand seven
stars. And out of his mouth went a sharp
two-edged sword, and his countenance was
as the sun shineth in his strength.
>> All right.
>> Okay. So,
>> like many
heavy voice. That's all. Okay.
>> And if you read a little more, it'll
tell you the seven spirits are seven
angels.
>> Yeah. You want to read that? That's that
verse 20.
>> Verse 20. Yeah.
Verse 20 says, "The mystery of the seven
stars which thou sawest in my right
hand, and the seven golden candlesticks,
the seven stars are the angels of the
seven churches. And the seven
candlesticks which thou sawest are the
seven churches."
>> And those seven stars, which are seven
angels, are also called the seven
spirits of God that run to and fro in
the earth.
Yep.
>> All right.
>> We hope that answered your question.
Next question. Next one. Sky Rider asks,
"What does do not resist an evil doer
mean?" And Matthew 5:39
is given.
>> Matthew 5 and 39. Let's go there.
Matthew 5
and verse 39.
Oh, okay. It's talking about turning the
cheeks. Matthew 5 and39.
Uh, pick it up, brother. Verse 38. Read
38 and 39.
Go ahead.
Ye have heard that it has been said, "An
eye for an eye, and a tooth for a
tooth." But I say unto you, that ye
resist not evil. But whosoever shall
smite thee on thy right cheek, turn to
him, the other also.
>> Open to the panel.
>> All it's saying is don't uh uh trade
evil for evil.
>> Right. That's right.
>> All that
>> do you wrong or do something to you
>> and uh uh if you don't have to defend
your your life
then you just walk away.
>> Let God takes vengeance.
>> Okay.
[clears throat]
>> But but the way was is like you do not
resist evil. What this really telling
you is you are to resist evil that you
don't do the same thing that a evil
person is doing to you.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> That's all it say. Don't reciprocate.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Hope that answered your question
there. Next question.
>> Next one. Mike Corley asks, "Being that
God holds us accountable at 20, will the
parent bear the iniquity of the child if
they sin prior to 20
>> Ezekiel 18th chapter
>> Ezekiel?"
>> Yep.
>> And where's one?
Ezekiel 18 and verse1 says the word of
the Lord came unto me again saying what
mean ye that ye use this proverb
concerning the land of Israel saying the
fathers have eaten sour grapes and the
children's teeth are set on edge
as I live sayeth the Lord God ye shall
not have occasion anymore to use this
proverb in Israel
behold All souls are mine. As the soul
of the father, so also the soul of the
son is mine. The soul that sinnth, it
shall die.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. Um
>> read read the verse 19.
>> Oh, read read through to verse 19.
>> No, just read verse 19.
>> Okay.
It says, "Yet say ye, why do not the son
bear the iniquity of the father? When
the son hath done that which is lawful
and right, and hath kept all my
statutes, and have done them, he shall
surely live."
>> The soul that sinnth, it shall die.
The Son shall not bear the iniquity of
the Father, neither shall the Father
bear the iniquity of the Son. The
righteousness of the righteous shall be
upon him, and the wickedness of the
wicked shall be upon him.
>> That's called
>> and that speaks for itself. But what the
Lord did with Israel when they come out
of Egypt,
that's a decision he made. I don't think
nobody can nobody can uh uh explain why
because it's not written why he held him
at 20 years and older. Like I say,
that's another one you make a note of
when you see the Lord, ask him why.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Hope that shed some light for you as we
continue to move on with time or
ticking.
>> Yes. Okay. Next one. Um June Norford
asks, "How does blessness of a wound
cleanses away evil?" And Proverbs 20
verse 30 is given.
>> Proverbs 20 and verse 30. Let's go
there. Proverbs 20
and verse 30. And read that question
again, Deborah.
>> Yes. How does bluess of a wound cleanses
away evil?
>> 20 and 30.
All right. Read it when you get there,
brother, and let's open it up to the
panel.
>> The blessness of a womb cleans cleanseth
away evil. So do stripes the inward
parts of the belly.
All that's saying is when a wound is a a
a physical wound turn blue, it's uh it's
you know it's getting well. It's
purifying. The same thing is you
supposed to be uh turn away strife
from not fighting and arguing with
people and just use the wound to let you
know how you like like it's being
healed. You supposed to be healing.
Don't get into no argument or fight with
people that you don't have to that uh
you don't have to. That's all it's
saying. But if anybody have anything
else, stay on.
>> Yeah. No.
Yeah. Let's get some bless from that
belt and that kind of kept me in line.
Kept some of that evil way off of me.
[laughter]
So, but um we hope that that answered
your question there as we continue to
move on to our next one.
>> All right, next one. Etica Males says,
"The Lord sits at the right hand of God.
However, during the stoning of Stefan,
he was standing instead."
any biblical significance meaning why
the Lord stood instead?
>> Open to the panel.
>> What is that? Acts seven.
>> Yeah, Acts 7 and uh let me see here.
Let's see.
and be around that. Um,
>> it's gonna be around
>> 59 is when they stone Stefan. But I'm
looking for
>> pick it up. Verse 55.
>> Okay. Acts 7 and verse 55 says, "But he
being full of the Holy Ghost looked up
steadfastly into heaven and saw the
glory of God and Jesus standing on the
right hand of God
and said, "Behold, I see the heavens
open and the Son of Man standing on the
right hand of God."
Then they cried out with a loud voice
and stopped their ears and ran upon him
with one accord.
>> Okay, James, hold it. Hold it there.
Deborah, what's that question again?
>> Right. Her question is, he was standing
instead. Any biblical significance
meaning why the Lord stood instead?
>> Uh, it just chose to do so.
There ain't nothing written.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> He just say saw a vision. He saw a
vision
>> before he died.
>> That's it. But why he's standing why
Jesus was standing at the right hand of
the father instead of sitting. We don't
know.
>> Right. Don't know. So we're going to get
in another question, Sister Deborah,
before time expire.
>> All right. Uh Charlotte T wants you to
explain Luke 16
vers 1 through 11.
>> Luke 16
verses 1
>> through 11.
>> 1-1.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
All right, James. just uh pick it up a
little bit and let's
>> okay
>> again at that Luke 16:1 and open it up
to the to the panel. Go ahead, brother.
>> Okay. And he said unto his disciples,
there was a certain rich man which had a
steward. And the same was accused unto
him that he was had wasted his goods.
And he called him and said unto him, How
is it that I hear of thee given account
of thy stewardship? for thou mayest be
no longer steward. Then the steward said
within himself, What shall I do? For my
Lord taketh away from me the
stewardship, I cannot dig to beg, I am
ashamed. I am resolved what to do, that
when I am put out of the stewardship
that may receive me into their houses.
So he called every one of his lords
debtors unto him and said unto the
first, "How much owest thou unto my
lord?" And he said, "1und measures of
oil." And he said unto them, "Take thy
bill, and sit down quickly, and write
50." Then said he to another, "How much
owest thou?" And he said, "Hund measures
of wheat." And he said unto him, "Take
thy bill and write for a score." And the
Lord commanded the unjust steward
because he had done wisely. For the
children of this world are in their
generation wiser than the children of
light. And I say unto you, make to
yourselves friends of the mammon of
unrighteousness, that when ye fail, they
may receive you into everlasting
habitations.
He that is faithful in that which is
least is faithful also in much. And he
that is unjust in the least is unjust
also in much. If therefore ye have not
been faithful in the unrighteous mammon,
who will commit to your trust the true
with riches?
>> Open to the panel
cuz I know that verse eight talks. Go
ahead, guess caller.
All he's really saying is if you going
to serve God, then serve him right. But
if you're not going to serve right, you
may well make friends of the world cuz
you still going to pay the cost of the
lake of fire.
>> All in, all out.
>> All that simple.
>> Yeah. All right. We hope that that
answered your question. And that
question has brought us to the end of
our program. Right, Sister Deborah?
>> That is correct. The time is 9:00.
>> All right. So, we like to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in with us this evening. We had a
lot of fun in fellowshipping with you
this evening. But we'd like to say if
you submitted a question and we didn't
have a chance to answer it, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah will take
it, put it in rotation, and we will
address that question next Wednesday.
So, thank you again, and until we all
come together again, be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as brother
James closes us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. In Jesus'
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.